dish.com 2017-12-02

# DISH Network L.L.C. Subscriber Privacy Notice

DISH Network L.L.C. Subscriber Privacy Notice
This Privacy Notice (“Notice”) explains how DISH Network L.L.C. (“DISH”) collects, uses and
discloses information about DISH subscribers. In the Notice, the terms “DISH”, “DISH Network”,
“we”, “us”, or “our” refer to DISH Network L.L.C., which owns and/or operates the DISH® direct
broadcast satellite television service and related services (the “Service”). The term “you” refers to
you as a subscriber to our satellite television service. Your use of the Service including through a
set-top box or satellite receiver and any related control device, any device authorized to receive our
services, or any software or mobile application constitutes your acceptance of this Notice.
This Notice does not apply to the areas of DISH websites that are available to the general public, the
dishNET satellite service or the dishNET wireline service, all of which are covered by separate privacy
notices. These notices can be found at dish.com/legal.
I.     Protection of Subscriber Information Under the Communications Act
As a subscriber to the DISH satellite television service, you are entitled under Section 338(i) of the
Communications Act of 1934 (the “Communications Act”) to know the following:
     • how DISH is limited in how we collect, use, and disclose personally identifiable information
       about you;
     • what personally identifiable information we collect about you and how we use it;
     • how, why, and when we disclose personally identifiable information about you and to whom;
     • how long we keep your personally identifiable information;
     • how you can access your personally identifiable information; and
     • your rights concerning your personally identifiable information and its collection, use and
       disclosure.
The Communications Act applies to personally identifiable information that you have given us, or
that we have collected in connection with your use of the Service. Personally identifiable
information is information that identifies you specifically; it does not include aggregate data,
anonymized data, or data that does not identify you or other particular individuals. This Notice
includes the information required to be disclosed under the Communications Act as well as certain
additional privacy-related information for DISH satellite television subscribers.
II.    What Information We Collect About You
The Communications Act allows DISH to use our satellite facilities to collect personally identifiable
information about you to obtain information necessary to provide our satellite television service or
other services to our subscribers and to detect unauthorized reception of satellite signals. The
Communications Act prevents us from using our satellite television system facilities to collect
personally identifiable information about you for any other reason without your prior written or
electronic consent.
       A. Personally Identifiable Information
In order to provide reliable, high quality service to you, we keep regular business records containing
information about you that may constitute personally identifiable information. These records generally
include the following information, among other things: your name, service address, billing address, e-
mail address, telephone number, social security number, bank account and/or credit card number,
                                                     1

and other account information.
We may also collect and maintain other information about your account, such as billing and payment
history, service information, customer correspondence and communications records, records
indicating the number of television sets and devices connected to our satellite facilities and the
programming service options you have chosen.
         B. Usage and Service Information
When you use the Service, our distribution systems automatically collect certain information
regarding your use of the Service. If, for example, you watch a pay-per-view program or purchase a
product or service, the system may collect certain personally identifiable information such as account
and billing-related information related to the pay-per-view programs or other products or services
ordered so that you may be properly billed for them. Most of the information that is collected is used
to carry out a particular request that you made in connection with the Service and is not personally
identifiable information. This information may include information required to change your television
channel, review listings in an electronic program guide, and pause or fast forward through certain
programs, among other information. It may also include other information such as the time you
actually use our services and the use of other features of our services, and which menus and menu
screens are used most often and the time spent using them, among other information. This
information may be in various formats, including electronic or audio format, and may be collected
through the set top box or satellite receiver in use, through related equipment such as a remote
control, or other devices through which you access the Service. DISH also obtains data related to
your viewing choices and advertisements selected for you. We periodically summarize, anonymize,
aggregate, and/or remove certain data elements from data sets that can be used to uniquely identify
you, and employ other similar methods designed to inhibit direct association with your identity.
         C. Third Party Information
We may also combine your personally identifiable information with personally identifiable information
obtained from third parties such as programmers, business partners and affiliates, consumer
reporting agencies, and other data companies for the purpose of creating enhanced databases,
business records, products, or service offerings. We may use these databases and these business
records in marketing, advertising, and other activities related to the Service and other products and
services. We also maintain records of research concerning subscriber satisfaction and viewing
habits, which are obtained from subscriber interviews and questionnaires.
         D. Third Party Services and Websites
When you click on a link to a third-party service, application, or website, even when doing so through
a DISH set-top box or website, this Notice no longer applies. You should review the privacy
statements of the third parties operating any such services, applications, or websites prior to providing
your personal information.
         E. Cookies and Other Technologies
The Service may be provided through Internet websites or other platforms operated by us, our
affiliates, and/or other companies. For example, you can access the Service from our websites and
                                                    2

apps and by using certain Internet-connected devices and other similar platforms that are not
operated or maintained by us. We are not responsible for the information, security, or privacy
practices of such third parties or any third-party platforms. If you are using the Service on a third-party
operated platform, you should check the privacy statement of the applicable third party to determine
how it handles any information it collects from or about you.
We may use cookies, web beacons, tags, and other technologies to make your use of the Service
more convenient and to support and improve our business, marketing, and advertising activities;
these technologies expand our and third parties’ abilities to collect data and other information. For
example, we may use cookies to remember your e-mail address so that you will not have to re-enter
this information each time you visit any of our websites or apps. Most browsers are initially set up to
accept cookies, but you can set up your browser to alert you every time a cookie is offered, letting
you decide whether to accept it. You can access the Service even when you’ve disabled certain
cookies, but you may not be automatically recognized by the Service upon re-visiting.
Some of our websites and HTML-formatted e-mails and e-newsletters use web beacons to compile
statistics about our website usage. You may be able to disable some web beacons by rejecting their
associated cookies. We also collect information that includes data such as IP addresses, browser
type, device type, Internet Service Provider, referring/exit pages, platform type, date/time stamp, and
number of clicks. DISH, our business partners, and our service providers use this information to
analyze trends, administer the Service, track usage and users’ movement in the aggregate, as well
as to gather broad demographic information.
We may use cookies, web beacons, tags, and other technologies to track, transmit, and analyze
usage information and to compile statistical information about our users in order to improve the quality
and performance of the Service. DISH reserves the right to publish non-personal information
regarding the Service for promotional purposes and as a representative audience. DISH does not
recognize “Do Not Track” requests from Internet browsers.
From time to time, we may allow you to use the Service with social networking services and connect
your Membership Account with accounts that you have with third parties, including with certain third-
party social networks (“Third-Party Accounts”). If you consent to share information about your
activities with Third-Party Accounts, then DISH may send information about you to such third parties.
DISH places advertisements on the Service and on third-party platforms, and also places
advertisements from third-party advertisers on the Service. Advertisers, advertising technology
companies, and service providers that perform advertising-related services for us and our business
partners may use cookies, web beacons, tags, and other technologies to collect information from or
about you in order to tailor advertisements, measure advertising effectiveness, and enable other
enhancements.
DISH may also permit third parties to collect certain information related to your usage of our Services,
such as viewer measurement and other data related to your activities for market research, ratings,
viewer measurement, and other analytical and reporting purposes. Our agreements with business
partners and service providers that collect information limit the types and use of information shared
with these companies.
                                                     3

III.   How We Use Your Information
We use personally identifiable information as permitted by the Communications Act and this Notice.
Among other things, we use this information primarily to conduct business activities related to
providing you the Service and to help us detect theft of service. Generally speaking, we use the
information that we collect in connection with billing and collections, administration, surveys,
marketing, service delivery and customization, maintenance and operations, and fraud prevention.
We may also use the personal and aggregate information about you to deliver addressable or
customized advertising, offers, and other services to you. We also use personally identifiable
information to, among other things:
     • install, operate, provide, and maintain our satellite television service and other services;
     • confirm that you are receiving the level(s) of service requested and are properly billed;
     • identify when changes are made to your account or services;
     • inform you of products, programming, or services that may be of interest to you;
     • make programming recommendations;
     • understand the use of, and identify improvements to, our services;
     • detect unauthorized reception of our services;
     • determine whether applicable policies and terms of service are being violated;
     • configure satellite television service-related devices;
     • perform statistical or qualitative research and analysis;
     • maintain our do not contact list;
     • comply with law; and
     • as otherwise necessary to provide the service.
IV.    Disclosure of Information to Others
DISH considers the personally identifiable information contained in our business records to be
confidential. The Communications Act permits us to disclose personally identifiable information
concerning any subscriber if the disclosure is:
       necessary for us to provide or conduct a legitimate business activity related to our
       satellite television service or other services provided to you; required by law or legal
       process (as described below); or of the names and addresses of subscribers for
       “mailing list” or other purposes (subject to each subscriber’s right to prohibit or limit
       this disclosure as described below).
       A. When DISH is Permitted to Disclose Personally Identifiable Information
                1. To conduct business activities related to providing you with our satellite
                   television services or other services
We may disclose personally identifiable information about you to our affiliates or to others who
work for us, such as outside auditors, professional advisors, service providers, and vendors;
potential business merger, acquisition, or sale partners; and regulators when the disclosure is
necessary to render or conduct a legitimate business activity related to the satellite television
service or other services that we provide to you. Generally, these disclosures involve billing and
                                                     4

collections, administration, surveys, marketing, service delivery and customization, maintenance
and operations, and fraud prevention. We may also share your information with third parties that
provide content or technologies used in our services to report on and account for the use of such
content or technologies by our subscribers. We may also disclose information about you in non-
personally identifiable or aggregate formats, such as ratings surveys and service usage and other
statistical reports, which do not personally identify you, your particular viewing habits, or the nature
of any transaction that you have made over the satellite television system. We may also use and
share data, including IP address, device ID, and other non-personally identifiable information, in
aggregate or anonymized formats with programmers, advertisers, and others for advertising and
other purposes. If we (or our parent company) enter into a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a
portion of our assets, in most instances our subscribers’ personally identifiable information will be
one of the items transferred as part of the transaction.
               2. For “mailing list” or other purposes
The Communications Act permits us to disclose limited personally identifiable information to others,
such as charities, marketing organizations, or other businesses, for satellite or non-satellite “mailing
list” or other purposes. From time to time we may disclose your name and address for these
purposes. Any “mailing list” and related disclosures that we may make are limited by the
Communications Act to disclosures of subscriber names and addresses where the disclosures do
not reveal, directly or indirectly, (i) the extent of any viewing or other use by the subscriber of a
satellite service or other service provided by us; or (ii) the nature of any transaction made by the
subscriber over any facilities used by us.
        B. When DISH is Required to Disclose Personally Identifiable Information
We make commercially reasonable efforts to protect your privacy as described in this Notice.
Nevertheless, we may be required by law to disclose personally identifiable information about you
without your consent and without notice in order to comply with a valid legal process such as a
subpoena, court order, or search warrant.
The Communications Act requires us to disclose personally identifiable information to a third party
or governmental entity in response to a court order. If the court order is sought by a governmental
entity, the Communications Act requires that you are afforded the opportunity to appear and contest
in a court proceeding relevant to the court order any claims made in support of the court order. At
such a proceeding, the Communications Act requires the governmental entity to offer clear and
convincing evidence that the subject of the information is reasonably suspected of engaging in
criminal activity and that the information sought would be material evidence in the case. In addition,
under the authority of an administrative subpoena, state welfare agencies may obtain the names,
addresses, and certain other information of individuals as they appear in the subscriber records of
the satellite company with respect to those who, for example, owe, or are owed, welfare or child
support. This information may be obtained without a court order and does not require that a
subscriber be given notice of and the opportunity to contest the disclosure.
We may also use or disclose personally identifiable information about you without your consent to
protect our customers, employees, or property; in emergency situations; and to enforce our rights
under our terms of service and policies, in court or elsewhere.
                                                     5

V.      How to Limit DISH’s Use and Disclosure of Your Personally Identifiable Information
You may at any time request us to prohibit or limit: 1) disclosure of your personally identifiable
information for “mailing list” purposes; 2) collection of viewer measurement data from your set-top
box; or 3) delivery of addressable advertisements to your set-top box that were selected for you
using your personally identifiable information. However, your request for us to prohibit or limit
addressable advertisements will not limit the quantity of advertisements in our services, but may
reduce the relevancy of such advertisements to you. To limit any of these uses, you must contact
us in writing at DISH Network L.L.C., Attn: PRIVACY, P.O. Box 6655, Englewood, CO 80155-6655.
Be sure to include your name, address, telephone number, and your DISH account number. The
written request should be signed by the person who is identified in our billing records as the
subscriber. If you have a joint account, a request by one party will apply to the entire account. If you
have multiple accounts, your notice must separately identify each account covered by the request.
VI.     How We Protect Your Personally Identifiable Information
We use commercially reasonable efforts to prevent unauthorized access to personally identifiable
information by anyone other than you or DISH. However, we cannot guarantee that these practices
will prevent every unauthorized attempt to access, use, or disclose personally identifiable information.
VII.    How Long We Maintain Your Personally Identifiable Information
DISH maintains personally identifiable information about you in our regular business records while
you are a subscriber to our satellite television service or other services and for a period of time after
you are no longer a subscriber if the information is necessary for the purposes for which it was
collected, to satisfy legal or tax requirements or for business purposes. If there are no pending
requests or court orders for access to this personally identifiable information, no other legal reasons
to retain such information, and no open items on a subscriber's account (e.g., balances due, credit
balances, unreturned or damaged equipment, etc.), then DISH destroys social security number and
bank account and/or credit card number information two (2) years after a former subscriber's last
account disconnect date or last payment transaction date, and other personally identifiable
information other than service address three (3) years following a subscriber's termination of DISH
services. DISH disassociates service address information from any remaining account information
seven (7) years after account disconnect date.
VIII.   Examining Personally Identifiable Information
You may examine your personally identifiable information we collect and maintain in our regular
business records (generally, billing and account information). If you wish to obtain a copy of the
information, please mail a written notarized request for a copy of your personally identifiable
information to DISH Network L.L.C., Attn: PRIVACY, P.O. Box 6655, Englewood, CO 80155-6655,
giving us a reasonable period of time to locate and prepare the information for your review. All
requests must include your DISH account number. We will mail the information to you at your current
billing address. You will be permitted to request only records that contain personally identifiable
information about you and no one else. In order to protect you and ensure that the request is being
made by the true person to whom the information pertains, we will process only notarized requests.
                                                     6

You will be provided a reasonable opportunity to correct errors if any of the personally identifiable
information is inaccurate.
IX.     Your Recourse for Violation of Your Privacy Rights
If you believe that you have been aggrieved by any act of ours in violation of the Communications Act
with respect to your personally identifiable information, you may bring an action seeking damages,
attorney’s fees, and litigation costs reasonably incurred. Any dispute relating to your privacy rights or
arising out of this Notice is subject to any dispute resolution procedures or provisions provided in your
Residential Customer Agreement.
X.      Changes to This Notice
We may modify this notice at any time. We will notify you of any material changes through written,
electronic, or other means as permitted by law.
Version: February 2017
                                                      7
